Where do you come from?
من أين أنت؟
It's such a simple question,
إنه سؤال بسيط للغاية
but these days, of course, simple questions
ولكن في هذه الأيام، بالطبع، الأسئلة البسيطة
bring ever more complicated answers.
تجلب إجابات أكثر تعقيدًا من أي وقت مضى
People are always asking me where I come from,
دومًا يسألني الناس من أين أنا
and they're expecting me to say India,
ويتوقعون مني أن أقول الهند
and they're absolutely right insofar as 100 percent
وهم محقون طبعًا ،حيث أنّ 100%
of my blood and ancestry does come from India.
من دمي وأسلافي من الهند
Except, I've never lived one day of my life there.
باستثناء أنني لم أعش يومًا واحدًا من حياتي هناك
I can't speak even one word
أنا لا أستطيع أن أقول كلمة واحدة
of its more than 22,000 dialects.
من اللهجات الهندية البالغ عددها 22،000
So I don't think I've really earned the right
ولذلك، لا أعتقد أنه يحق لي
to call myself an Indian.
أن أصف نفسي بأنني هندي
And if "Where do you come from?"
وإذا كان السؤال "من أين أنت؟"
means "Where were you born and raised and educated?"
يعنى "أين ولدت وترعرعت وتعلمت؟"
then I'm entirely of that funny little country
فهذا يعنى أنني وبكل تاكيد من ذلك البلد العجيب
known as England,
المعروف بـ إنجلترا
except I left England as soon as I completed
باستثناء أني تركت إنجلترا بمجرد أن أكملت
my undergraduate education,
تعليمي الجامعي،
and all the time I was growing up,
ودوماً خلال نشأتي
I was the only kid in all my classes
كنت الولد الوحيد في كل الصفوف
who didn't begin to look like the classic English heroes
الذى لم يشبه الأبطال الإنجليز القدامى
represented in our textbooks.
المستعرَضة سيرتهم في كتبنا المدرسية.
And if "Where do you come from?"
وإذا كان السؤال "من أين أنت؟"
means "Where do you pay your taxes?
يعني "أين تدفع الضرائب؟
Where do you see your doctor and your dentist?"
أين ترى طبيبك وطبيب أسنانك؟"
then I'm very much of the United States,
فإنني إلى حد كبير من الولايات المتحدة،
and I have been for 48 years now,
ولقد أتممت 48 سنة هناك حتى الآن،
since I was a really small child.
منذ كنت طفلاً صغيرًا جداً.
Except, for many of those years,
إلّا أنه لكثير من تلك السنوات،
I've had to carry around this funny little pink card
كان عليّ أن أحمل هذه البطاقة الصغيرة الوردية المضحكة
with green lines running through my face
وفيها خطوط خضراء تمر على صورة وجهي عليها
identifying me as a permanent alien.
والتي تعرفني كـ"غريب دائم".
I do actually feel more alien the longer I live there.
وبالفعل، يزداد شعوري بالغربة كلما طالت فترة بقائي هناك.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
And if "Where do you come from?"
وإذا كان "من أين أنت؟"
means "Which place goes deepest inside you
تعني "أي مكان يتغلغل في أعماقك
and where do you try to spend most of your time?"
وأين تحاول قضاء معظم وقتك؟"
then I'm Japanese,
فإنني إذن ياباني،
because I've been living as much as I can
لأن عشت كلما أمكنني
for the last 25 years in Japan.
أثناء السنوات الـ 25 الماضية في اليابان.
Except, all of those years I've been there on a tourist visa,
إلاّ أنني كنت هناك بتأشيرة سياحية طيلة تلك السنوات ،
and I'm fairly sure not many Japanese
وأنا متأكد تمامًا أنه لا يوجد الكثير من اليابانيين
would want to consider me one of them.
ممن قد يعتبرونني واحدًا منهم.
And I say all this just to stress
وأنا أقول كل هذا فقط للتشديد على
how very old-fashioned and straightforward
كم هي تقليديه جدًا وواضحة
my background is,
خلفيتي،
because when I go to Hong Kong or Sydney or Vancouver,
لأنه عندما أذهب إلى هونغ كونغ أو سيدني أو فانكوفر،
most of the kids I meet
معظم الأطفال الذين أقابلهم
are much more international and multi-cultured than I am.
هم أكثر عالميّه وتعددية ثقافية منّي.
And they have one home associated with their parents,
ولديهم موطن ما مرتبط بآبائهم،
but another associated with their partners,
لكن هناك آخر مرتبط مع أقرانهم،
a third connected maybe with the place where they happen to be,
وموطن ثالث مرتبط ربما بالمكان الذي يوجدون فيه،
a fourth connected with the place they dream of being,
ورابع مرتبط بالمكان الذي يحلمون به،
and many more besides.
إضافةَ الى أماكن أخرى كثيره.
And their whole life will be spent taking pieces
وسوف تنقضي حياتهم بأكملها في أخذ اجزاء
of many different places and putting them together
من كثير من الاماكن المختلفه وجمعها معاً
into a stained glass whole.
لتكوّن قطعه متكامله كزجاجٍ ملوّن.
Home for them is really a work in progress.
الوطن بالنسبة لهم هو عمل قيد التنفيذ
It's like a project on which they're constantly adding
إنه مثل المشروع الذي يضيفون إليه باستمرار
upgrades and improvements and corrections.
التحديثات والتحسينات والتعديلات.
And for more and more of us,
وبالنسبة للكثير والكثير منا،
home has really less to do with a piece of soil
فإن ارتباط الوطن بقطعه من التراب هو أضعف
than, you could say, with a piece of soul.
من ارتباطه، اذا جاز القول، بقطعة من الروح.
If somebody suddenly asks me, "Where's your home?"
إذا فاجأني شخص بسؤالٍ، "أين هو منزلك؟"
I think about my sweetheart or my closest friends
يخطر ببالي حبيبتي أو اصدقائي المقربين
or the songs that travel with me wherever I happen to be.
أو الأغاني التي تسافر معي أينما حللت .
And I'd always felt this way,
وهذا هو ما أَحسست به دوماً،
but it really came home to me, as it were,
ولكني أدركت هذا الإحساس، على الواقع،
some years ago when I was climbing up the stairs
قبل بضع سنوات حينما كنت أصعد السلم
in my parents' house in California,
في منزل والداي في كاليفورنيا،
and I looked through the living room windows
ونظرت من خلال نوافذ غرفة الجلوس
and I saw that we were encircled by 70-foot flames,
ورأيت أننا كنا مطوقين بلهيب يعلو 70-قدمًا،
one of those wildfires that regularly tear through
احدى تلك الحرائق التي تندلع بانتظام في
the hills of California and many other such places.
تلال كاليفورنيا والعديد من الأماكن المشابهة الأخرى.
And three hours later, that fire had reduced
وبعد ثلاث ساعات، حوّلت تلك النار
my home and every last thing in it
منزلي وكل ما احتواه
except for me to ash.
باستثنائي أنا الى رماد.
And when I woke up the next morning,
وعندما استيقظت في صباح اليوم التالي،
I was sleeping on a friend's floor,
كنت نائماً على الارض عند صديقي،
the only thing I had in the world was a toothbrush
وكان الشيء الوحيد المتبقي لي في العالم هو فرشاة أسنان
I had just bought from an all-night supermarket.
اشتريتها للتو من احد المتاجر المفتوحه طوال الليل.
Of course, if anybody asked me then,
طبعاً، لو سُئلت عندئذٍ،
"Where is your home?"
"أين هو منزلك؟"
I literally couldn't point to any physical construction.
أنا حرفيا لا استطيع الاشاره إلى أي بناء مادي.
My home would have to be whatever I carried around inside me.
بيتي عندئذ كان ما أحمله في جعبتي.
And in so many ways, I think this is a terrific liberation.
وبالعديد من الطرق، اعتقد أنّ ذلك كان تحريراً رائعاً.
Because when my grandparents were born,
لأنه عندما ولد أجدادي،
they pretty much had their sense of home,
كان، الى حد كبير، احساسهم بالوطن،
their sense of community, even their sense of enmity,
إحساسهم بالمجتمع، حتى الشعور بالعداوة،
assigned to them at birth,
محدداً مسبقاً عند ولادتهم،
and didn't have much chance of stepping outside of that.
ولم يكن لديهم أي فرصة للتخلص من ذلك.
And nowadays, at least some of us can choose our sense of home,
وفي الوقت الحاضر، بعضنا،على الأقل، يمكننا اختيار إحساسنا بالوطن،
create our sense of community,
خلق إحساسنا بالمجتمع،
fashion our sense of self, and in so doing
تفصيل إحساسنا بالذات، وبذلك ربما
maybe step a little beyond
نكون أخذنا خطوة لتجاوز
some of the black and white divisions
بعض الحدود بين بيضاء و سوداء
of our grandparents' age.
من عصر أجدادنا.
No coincidence that the president
ليس من قبيل المصادفة أن رئيس
of the strongest nation on Earth is half-Kenyan,
أقوى أمة على الأرض هو من والد كيني الاصل،
partly raised in Indonesia,
تربى لفترةٍ في إندونيسيا،
has a Chinese-Canadian brother-in-law.
وله نسيب كندي-صيني الاصل.
The number of people living in countries not their own
عدد الأشخاص الذين يعيشون في بلدان غير بلدانهم
now comes to 220 million,
يقارب الآن 220 مليون،
and that's an almost unimaginable number,
وهذا عدد لا يمكن تصوره تقريبا،
but it means that if you took the whole population of Canada
ولكنه يعني أنه إذا أخذت كل سكان كندا
and the whole population of Australia
وكل سكان أستراليا
and then the whole population of Australia again
وبعد ذلك سكان أستراليا مرة أخرى
and the whole population of Canada again
وجميع سكان كندا مرة أخرى
and doubled that number,
وضاعفت المجموع،
you would still have fewer people than belong
لكان الناتج اقل من عدد الناس المنتمين
to this great floating tribe.
لهذه القبيلة العظيمه العائمه.
And the number of us who live outside
وعدد الأميركيين الذين يعيشون خارج
the old nation-state categories is increasing so quickly,
حدود الدول القومية القديمة يتزايد بسرعة،
by 64 million just in the last 12 years,
بما يعادل 64 مليون في السنوات الاثنتي عشرة الماضية فقط،
that soon there will be more of us than there are Americans.
أي أنه قريباً سيصبح تعدادنا أكثر من تعداد الامريكان.
Already, we represent the fifth-largest nation on Earth.
حالياً، نحن نمثل خامس أكبر أُمّه على الأرض.
And in fact, in Canada's largest city, Toronto,
وفي الحقيقه، في أكبر مدينة في كندا، تورنتو،
the average resident today is what used to be called
فإن متوسط المواطنين اليوم هم من كانوا يعرفون
a foreigner, somebody born in a very different country.
كغرباء، أي أنهم ولدوا في بلدٍ آخر مختلف.
And I've always felt that the beauty of being surrounded by the foreign
وقد شعرت دائماً أن حلاوة أن تكون محاطاً بالاجانب
is that it slaps you awake.
هي أنها تبققيك يقظاً
You can't take anything for granted.
لا يوجد شيء مضمون.
Travel, for me, is a little bit like being in love,
السفر، بالنسبة لي، يشبه الوقوع في الحب،
because suddenly all your senses are at the setting marked "on."
لأنه فجأة تنقلب جميع أحاسيسك الى حالة اشتعال.
Suddenly you're alert to the secret patterns of the world.
فجأة تمسي واعياً انماط العالم المخفيّه.
The real voyage of discovery, as Marcel Proust famously said,
الرحلة الحقيقية للاكتشاف،حسب مقولة مارسيل بروست الشهيرة،
consists not in seeing new sights,
هي ليست في رؤية مشاهد جديدة،
but in looking with new eyes.
لكنها النظر بعيون جديدة.
And of course, once you have new eyes,
وطبعا، بمجرد أن يصبح لديك عيون جديدة،
even the old sights, even your home
فإن المشاهد القديمة، وحتى منزلك
become something different.
تصبح شيئا مختلفاً.
Many of the people living in countries not their own
كثير من الناس الذين يعيشون في بلدان غير بلدانهم
are refugees who never wanted to leave home
هم من اللاجئين الذين لم يريدوا ابداً مغادرة وطنهم
and ache to go back home.
ويتشوقون للعودة إلى ديارهم.
But for the fortunate among us,
ولكن للمحظوظين منّا،
I think the age of movement brings exhilarating new possibilities.
أعتقد أن تلك التنقلات تجلب فرص مبهجه.
Certainly when I'm traveling,
وبالتأكيد عندما أسافر،
especially to the major cities of the world,
لا سيما الى المدن الرئيسية في العالم،
the typical person I meet today
فإن الشخص الاعتيادي الذي التقيه اليوم
will be, let's say, a half-Korean, half-German young woman
سوف تكون، مثلاً، امرأة شابه نصف-كورية، ونصف-ألمانية
living in Paris.
تعيش في باريس.
And as soon as she meets a half-Thai,
وحالما تلتقي شاباً نصف-تايلاندي،
half-Canadian young guy from Edinburgh,
نصف-كندي من أدنبرة،
she recognizes him as kin.
فإنها تعامله مثل الأقرباء.
She realizes that she probably has much more in common with him
لأنها تدرك أن بينهما من التشابه أكثر
than with anybody entirely of Korea or entirely of Germany.
منه مع أي شخص كان كورياً خالصاً ام ألمانياً خالصاً.
So they become friends. They fall in love.
وهكذا يصبحون أصدقاء. ويقعون في الحب.
They move to New York City.
يرحلون الى مدينة نيويورك.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
Or Edinburgh.
أو أدنبرة.
And the little girl who arises out of their union
والفتاة الصغيرة التي تنشأ من اتحادهما
will of course be not Korean or German
بالطبع لن تكون كورية أو المانية
or French or Thai or Scotch or Canadian
أو فرنسية أو تايلاندية أو سكوتلانديه أو كندية
or even American, but a wonderful
أو حتى أمريكيه، ولكن ستكون
and constantly evolving mix of all those places.
خليطاً رائعاً دائم الارتقاء من جميع هذه الأماكن.
And potentially, everything about the way
ومن المحتمل، أن الطريقه التي
that young woman dreams about the world,
تحلم بها هذه الفتاة في هذه الدنيا
writes about the world, thinks about the world,
وما تكتبه عن العالم، وكيفما تفكر في العالم،
could be something different,
يمكن أن تكون شيئا مختلفاً،
because it comes out of this almost unprecedented
لأنها نابعه من مزيجٍ من الثقافات
blend of cultures.
غير مألوف سابقاً.
Where you come from now is much less important
( من اين جئت؟ ) أقل أهميةً الآن
than where you're going.
من ( الى أين أنت ذاهب؟ ).
More and more of us are rooted in the future
المزيد والمزيد منا تضرب جذوره في المستقبل
or the present tense as much as in the past.
أو في الحاضر قدر ما هي في الماضي.
And home, we know, is not just the place
والمنزل، كما نعلم، ليست مجرد مكان
where you happen to be born.
صدف أن ولدتَ فيه.
It's the place where you become yourself.
إنه المكان الذي تحقق فيه ذاتك.
And yet,
وحتى الآن،
there is one great problem with movement,
هناك مشكلة كبيرة مع الترحال،
and that is that it's really hard to get your bearings
وهذا هو أنه من الصعب حقاً أن تحدد اتجاهك
when you're in midair.
عندما تكون في الجو.
Some years ago, I noticed that I had accumulated
منذ بضع سنوات، لاحظت أني قد جمعت
one million miles on United Airlines alone.
1 مليون كيلومتر على "الخطوط الجوية المتحدة" وحدها.
You all know that crazy system,
تعرفون كلكم ذلك النظام المعتوه،
six days in hell, you get the seventh day free.
ستة أيام في الجحيم، تحصل اليوم السابع مجاناً.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
And I began to think that really,
ولقد بدأت أعتقد فعلاً،
movement was only as good as the sense of stillness
ان الترحال رائع فقط بقدر الإحساس بالهدوء
that you could bring to it to put it into perspective.
الذي يمكنك الحصول عليه لتضع الأمور في منظورها الصحيح.
And eight months after my house burned down,
بعد أن احترق بيتي بثمانية أشهر،
I ran into a friend who taught at a local high school,
صادفت صديقاً كان يُدرّس في مدرسة ثانوية محلية،
and he said, "I've got the perfect place for you."
وقال " وجدت المكان المثالي لك."
"Really?" I said. I'm always a bit skeptical
"حقاً؟" قلتُ. أنا دائماً متشكك قليلاً
when people say things like that.
عندما يتفوه الناس بأشياء من هذا القبيل.
"No, honestly," he went on,
"لا صدقاً"، تابع القول،
"it's only three hours away by car,
"يبعد ثلاث ساعات فقط بالسيارة،
and it's not very expensive,
وليس مكلفاً جداً،
and it's probably not like anywhere you've stayed before."
وعلى الأرجح أنه لا يشبه أي مكان نزلت فيه من قبل ".
"Hmm." I was beginning to get slightly intrigued. "What is it?"
"همهمه". بدأ يجذب اهتمامي. "ما هذا المكان؟"
"Well —" Here my friend hemmed and hawed —
"حسنا —" هنا صديقي تردد وتأتأ —
"Well, actually it's a Catholic hermitage."
"حسنا، في الحقيقه هو ديرٌ كاثوليكي".
This was the wrong answer.
وكان ذاك جواباً خاطئاً.
I had spent 15 years in Anglican schools,
أمضيت 15 عاماً في مدارس الكنيسة الأنجليكانية،
so I had had enough hymnals and crosses to last me a lifetime.
لذا هناك من التراتيل والصلبان ما يكفيني عمرا كاملاً.
Several lifetimes, actually.
عدّة أعمارٍ، في الواقع.
But my friend assured me that he wasn't Catholic,
ولكن صديقي أكد لي أنه لم يكن كاثوليكياً،
nor were most of his students,
ومعظم طلابه لم يكونوا كذلك،
but he took his classes there every spring.
لكنه اخذ صفوفه هناك كل ربيع.
And as he had it, even the most restless, distractible,
وكما لاحظ، فإنه حتى أكثر الصبية اضطرابا، وتشتتا ،
testosterone-addled 15-year-old Californian boy
وغرقاً بالهرمونات (التستوستيرون) من عمر ال15 من أولاد كاليفورنيا
only had to spend three days in silence
لم يكن عليه سوى قضاء ثلاثة أيام في صمت
and something in him cooled down and cleared out.
حتى يبرد شيءٌ ما في داخله ويصفى.
He found himself.
يجد ذاته.
And I thought, "Anything that works for a 15-year-old boy
ففكرت، "ما يساعد صبياً في الخامسه عشره من العمر
ought to work for me."
لابد أن يأتني بالفائده ".
So I got in my car, and I drove three hours north
وهكذا ركبت سيّارتي وقدتها ثلاثِ ساعاتٍ شمالاً
along the coast,
بمحاذاة الساحل،
and the roads grew emptier and narrower,
أمست الطريق فارغةً وأضيق فأضيق،
and then I turned onto an even narrower path,
ثم انعطفت الى مسار أشد ضيقاً،
barely paved, that snaked for two miles
بالكاد مرصوف، امتد كالأفعى طول ميلين
up to the top of a mountain.
ارتفاعاً الى قمةِ جبل.
And when I got out of my car,
وعندما خرجت من سيارتي،
the air was pulsing.
كان الهواء يتدافع.
The whole place was absolutely silent,
كان المكان صامتاً تماماً،
but the silence wasn't an absence of noise.
لكن الصمت لم يكن غياب الضجيج.
It was really a presence of a kind of energy or quickening.
كان حقيقةً حضوراً لنوعٍ من الطاقه أو النشاط.
And at my feet was the great, still blue plate
بموازاة قدميّ كانت صفحةٌ زرقاء ساكنه
of the Pacific Ocean.
من المحيط الهادئ.
All around me were 800 acres of wild dry brush.
ومن حولي 800 فدان من الاشجار البريّه الجافه
And I went down to the room in which I was to be sleeping.
فنزلت الى غرفتي التي أنام فيها.
Small but eminently comfortable,
صغيرة ولكن مريحة للغايه،
it had a bed and a rocking chair
فيها سرير وكرسي هزاز
and a long desk and even longer picture windows
ومكتب طويل وأطول منه كانت النافذه
looking out on a small, private, walled garden,
المطله على حديقةٍ صغيرةٍ مطوّقه بجدار
and then 1,200 feet of golden pampas grass
من ثمَّ 1,200 قدم من نبات البامبس الذهبي
running down to the sea.
يمتد نزولاً حتى البحر.
And I sat down, and I began to write,
جلست، وبدأت اكتب،
and write, and write,
واكتب، واكتب،
even though I'd gone there really to get away from my desk.
مع أني قد ذهبت هناك لأهرب بعيداً عن مكتبي.
And by the time I got up, four hours had passed.
وعندما نهضتُ، أربع ساعات كانت قد مرّت.
Night had fallen,
هبط الليل،
and I went out under this great overturned saltshaker of stars,
وخرجت تحت هذه المملحة المقلوبه من النجوم،
and I could see the tail lights of cars
كان بإمكاني رؤية أضواء السيارات الخلفيه
disappearing around the headlands 12 miles to the south.
وهي تختفي خلف روؤس التلال 12 ميل جنوباً
And it really seemed like my concerns of the previous day
وبالفعل تهيأ لي أن مخاوفي من يوم أمس
vanishing.
بدأت تتلاشي.
And the next day, when I woke up
وفي اليوم التالي، عندما استيقظت
in the absence of telephones and TVs and laptops,
في غياب الهواتف وأجهزة التلفزيون وأجهزة الكمبيوتر المحمولة،
the days seemed to stretch for a thousand hours.
تبدو الأيام وكأنها تمتد لألف ساعة.
It was really all the freedom I know when I'm traveling,
كانت حقاً كل الحرية التي عرفتها خلال سفري
but it also profoundly felt like coming home.
وايضاً شعرت بشده كأني عدت الى بيتي.
And I'm not a religious person,
وأنا لست شخصاً متديناً
so I didn't go to the services.
لذا لم احضر الشعائر.
I didn't consult the monks for guidance.
لم أشاور الرهبان للتوجيه.
I just took walks along the monastery road
انا فقط تمشّيت على طريق الدير
and sent postcards to loved ones.
وارسلت البطاقات البريدية للأحباء.
I looked at the clouds,
تأملت في الغيوم،
and I did what is hardest of all for me to do usually,
وفعلت أصعب شيء من الممكن ان أفعله عادةً،
which is nothing at all.
وهو لا شيء على الإطلاق.
And I started to go back to this place,
وبدأت بالتردد على هذا المكان،
and I noticed that I was doing my most important work there
ولاحظت أني انجز أهمَّ اعمالي هناك
invisibly just by sitting still,
بخفاء وفقط بالجلوس هادئاً،
and certainly coming to my most critical decisions
وبالتأكيد اتخذت بعضاً من اهم قراراتي
the way I never could when I was racing
بطريقةٍ لم تكن ممكنه عندما كنت اتراكض
from the last email to the next appointment.
من آخر بريد إلكتروني إلى الموعد التالي.
And I began to think that something in me
ولقد بدأت أعتقد أن شيئا في داخلي
had really been crying out for stillness,
كان بحاجةٍ حقيقيّه للسكينه،
but of course I couldn't hear it
ولكن بالطبع لم أستطع أن أسمع
because I was running around so much.
لأني كنت اركض كثيراً.
and then complains that he can't see a thing.
ثم يشكو أنه لايستطيع رؤية أي شيء.
And I thought back to that wonderful phrase
وتذكرت تلك العبارة الرائعة
I had learned as a boy from Seneca,
التي سمعتها في صِغري من سينيكا،
in which he says, "That man is poor
يقول فيها، "أن الرجل فقيرٌ
not who has little but who hankers after more."
ليس لأنّه يملك القليل لكن لأنه يبغي المزيد. "
And, of course, I'm not suggesting
و بالطبع، أنا لا اقترح
that anybody here go into a monastery.
أن يذهب أي شخص هنا إلى دير.
That's not the point.
ذلك ليس الهدف.
But I do think it's only by stopping movement
ولكني أعتقد أنه بالتوقف عن الحركه فقط
that you can see where to go.
يمكنك أن ترى إلى أين تذهب.
And it's only by stepping out of your life and the world
وفقط عندما تخطو خارج حياتك وخارج العالم
that you can see what you most deeply care about
يمكنك أن ترى اكثر ما تهتمُّ لأجلهِ
and find a home.
ويمكنك أن تجد بيتاً.
And I've noticed so many people now
ولقد لاحظت الكثير من الناس الآن
take conscious measures to sit quietly for 30 minutes
يتخذون بوعيٍ تدابير للجلوس بهدوء لمدة 30 دقيقة
every morning just collecting themselves
كل صباح يستجمعون أنفسهم
in one corner of the room without their devices,
في إحدى زوايا الغرفة دون الأجهزة الخاصة بهم،
or go running every evening,
أو يذهبون عدواً كل مساء،
or leave their cell phones behind
أو يتركون هواتفهم المحموله خلفهم
when they go to have a long conversation with a friend.
عندما يذهبون للتحدّث مطوّلاً مع صديق.
Movement is a fantastic privilege,
التنقل ميزة رائعة،
and it allows us to do so much that our grandparents
وسمح لنا بعمل الكثير مما لم يكن أجدادنا
could never have dreamed of doing.
قادرين حتى أن يحلموا به.
But movement, ultimately,
لكن التنقل، في نهاية المطاف،
only has a meaning if you have a home to go back to.
له معنى فقط إن كان لديك منزل ترجع إليه.
And home, in the end, is of course
والمنزل، في النهاية،هو بالطبع
not just the place where you sleep.
ليس المكان الذي تنام فيه فقط.
It's the place where you stand.
إنه المكان حيث يمكنك الوقوف.
Thank you.
شكرًا لكم.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)